The truth is complicated.
Traitor is a drama, action, thriller film directed by Jeffrey Nachmanoff.
When straight arrow FBI agent Roy Clayton heads up the investigation into a dangerous
international conspiracy, all clues seem to lead back to former U.S.
Special Operations officer Samir Horn.
Samir Horn, played by Don Cheadle.
Roy Clayton, played by Guy Pearce.
Max Archer, played by Neal McDonough.
Omar, played by Saïd Taghmaoui.
Carter, played by Jeff Daniels.
Fareed Mansour, played by Alyy Khan.
Traitor is a 2008 American spy thriller film written and directed by
Jeffrey Nachmanoff, based on a story by Steve Martin.
In the film, a former Sudanese-American soldier (Don Cheadle) with a background in explosives is the prime suspect in a search by
an FBI Special Agent (Guy Pearce) for the bomb-maker in a string of global terror explosions aimed at civilians.
The film was released on August 27, 2008.
It received generally positive reviews from critics and
grossed $27 million against its $22 million budget.
The film explores themes of prison, escape, bomb, alcohol, faith.
The tone is emotional and intense.